A. Conger Goodyear Papers
A. Conger Goodyear Papers
1925-1963
Goodyear, A. Conger (Anson Conger), 1877-1964.
0.5 linear ft.
A. Conger Goodyear was a businessman from Buffalo and a founder of the Museum of Modern Art in New York City. Papers include biographical material, 1955; memorabilia, 1925-63; and published material by and about Goodyear, 1938-58.
149014
Biographical History
A. Conger Goodyear (1877-1964) was an American manufacturer and businessman. Born in Buffalo, New York on June 20, 1877, he received his A.B. degree from Yale University in 1899 and married Mary Forman on Jun 29, 1904. He began in the manufacturing business in 1900 and subsequently served as chairman of the board of directors of Gaylord Container Corporation, director of Paramount Pictures, director of G. M. & O. railroad, and department commander of the A.R.C. in the Pacific Ocean area. He served as a colonel in World War I and was the personal representative of the Secretary of War. He was a Major General in the First Division of the New York Guard, a president and trustee of the Museum of Modern Art in New York City, director of the Buffalo Academy of Fine Arts, and governor of the New York Hospital. He was also a member of several clubs, including Alpha Delta Phi, Wolf's Head (at Yale), the Links Club, and the Saturn Club in Buffalo. He was married twice and had four children. He died on April 24, 1964.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The A. Conger Goodyear Papers consists of biographical material, subject files, and published material. Biographical material consists of an autobiography and various citations which make note of Goodyear's career and service to mankind. Subject files contains exhibitions notices, a brochure, a memorandum, and two speeches awarding medals to Goodyear. In some cases, Goodyear had a hand in writing the exhibition catalogues, as is noted in the material. Published material contains books written about and by Goodyear, a book review, and magazine articles by and about Goodyear.
Arrangement of the Collection
All material is arranged alphabetically by subject.
Related Material
has made a concerted effort over the years to ensure that its manuscript and rare books holdings complement each other. As a result, many of our manuscript collections are supported by books, pamphlets, serials and other items which are cataloged in the Rare Books Collection. Please be sure to search for these related materials.
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; New York State; Goodyear family.; Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.); Businessmen, United States.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of A. Conger Goodyear, 1964.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Subject files
  - Brochure, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Exhibition notices, 1925; 1963,; undated (Box 1)
  - Exhibition notices written by Goodyear, 1925; undated (Box 1)
  - Memorandum re: sale of Goodyear's autograph collection, 1927 (Box 1)
  - Speeches
    - Awarding of Chancellor's Medal to Goodyear, 1955 (Box 1)
    - Awarding of Cross of Officier of the Legion of Honor to Goodyear, undated (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Books about
    - The Autograph Collection of A. C. Goodyear, undated (Box 1)
  - Books by
    - Family History by a Descendant, Part 1, undated (Box 1)
    - Family History by a Descendant, Part 2, undated (Box 1)
    - John George Milburn Jr.: A Memoir, 1938 (Box 1)
    - Museum of Modern Art: The First Ten Years, 1943 (Box 1)
    - One Wide Expanse, undated (Box 1)
    - Sidelights, undated (Box 1)
    - Tramping for Hoover, undated (Box 1)
  - Book reviews
    - Undated (Box 1)
  - Magazine articles about
    - Bulletin of the Museum of Modern Art, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Magazine articles by
    - The Niagara Frontier, 1957 (Box 1)
    - The Niagara Frontier, 1958 (Box 1)